I think most people probably do this the
opposite and do their live video after
they practice like hey let's pop on
YouTube do a practice run before I
record it from the Facebook group I've
already done it a few times and then I
put my whiteboard actually up on the
wall instead of sideways for six years
here I thought that the saving the world
did require two rules in mind
all right so many people how many people
save the world cuz normally I draw
perfect circles perfect as you will see
on the next ones members so million
members paying $10 a month each and
committing to one hour on our social
media so they can keep up to date both
like as easy is going on Facebook and
liking friends posts that's the hour you
have to commit an hour per month in
order to stay an active member we did in
that million so that gives us 10 million
dollars a month to save the world but we
then have I'm doing this and just as
like 10% 10% just because it makes the
easy math and I think it's that's the
word doable like if only 10% of the
people do this 10 percent of the people
do that I don't think that's an
overarching thing so 10 percent will be
to keep doing this the wrong course so
these people will let's say do
and there's a hundred thousand so that
is either they just spend ten hours
online finding out what which is again
only two and a half hours per week we'd
all pretty much do that more than that
on Facebook I think just regularly but
hundreds people the idea is that ten
hours a week is more concentrated but
everyone's only doing what they want to
do so it's it's just like one Facebook
right we're not working or just having
fun about doing what we want to do and
then all of a sudden we've wasted 10
hours in that same way but like we can
still book calls out for things that I
actually need to get done and the people
who want to volunteer for that can do it
these few inner circles or not maybe so
I just like doing 10% and 10% so then we
have 10,000 people who put in say 20
hours per month and again doing things
that they they want to be doing so it
doesn't feel like work to them again
it's 20 hours per month is still only 5
hours per week then you have 1,000
people for 40 hours like again these are
rough estimates and things where like I
think that more like we have a million
people sign out there's gonna be more
than a hundred thousand who want to put
in ten hours it's gonna be but this is
under estimating not to show that it's
so thousand people that's one in a
thousand because a thousand or two
thousand one in a thousand people
putting in 40 hours per month doing 10
hours it's just like what naturally this
is how we naturally fall right but you
don't oh it's better spent central
circles before I get on to the next part
so then you have 100 people who are the
employees these people aren't
necessarily doing hopefully as much as
possible they're doing what's easy and
lightly fun for them but they're being
paid so now we have to ask them to do
maybe a bit above and beyond what
they're just gonna naturally do because
we're paying them or distressing their
lives
with money so that they can put their
time and expertise in severance maybe
this thousand hours
some people who they're pretty forty
hours per month they possibly also be
getting paid or getting more perks or
getting more like you don't get to just
choose that you're an employee any more
than you but like you're invited to be
the one in a million and then you get to
choose how much work you do right if
you're you don't get to be an employee
unless you're one of those thousand
right unless you're someone who puts in
48 hours a month volunteering for free
showing that you're the kind of person
who wants to be here and wants to find
you're not probably get to be an
employee also where people are more of
an expert like it would take me a week
of solid time to do a task and I'm like
yeah okay I'll do it but only if I get
paid for it let someone else I'd be able
to you know spend three hours doing that
employees then we have the board of
directors which are ten people and those
board of directors every year we have a
ATD tension Board of Directors
determined by a snapshot of democracy so
let's say June 1st every year
whoever you delegate your vote to the
top ten people who have the most votes
delegated to them become the board of
directors for the next year but we get
to choose which one of those Board of
Directors has our delegated boat so that
they can sit at the table and represent
us we can also hold on once the
technology is in place it can also hold
on to our boat because everybody all
million members have access to the same
information once we have the technology
to do that so the board of directors
doesn't have this internal information
that everyone doesn't have access to and
then they have to you have to trust that
they're working in our best interests
cuz we can see whether or not they work
in their best interest cuz they're
saying hey I voted this way because of
all of this evidence that you guys
provided right because you guys said
this is the way you should vote so
that's that's and everyone's in the one
is are there a million people out there
who would pay $10 a month and co-create
with another the other nine hundred nine
hundred and ninety nine thousand nine
hundred ninety nine people that's what
that is right like who wants to go great
yes I think that it's the question is
how big of a pool do we need this to go
to the find are 1 billion people is it 1
in 10 people that is an uber cooperator
and what would want to do this is it one
in a thousand twenty two million it's
one in a million we're screwed because
we don't have a million a million people
on this planet if it's one in ten people
or one in a hundred people and this
needs to go to one not this video but
the video that explains that a single
spiral needs to go out to ten million
people to get 1 million people signed on
now the truth is you can start this with
a lot less than 1 million people and
we're kind of starting here and we're
here our way out
but the reason 1 million is inspiring is
you then have 10 million dollars a month
to work with and a lot of what I'm doing
is this threshold business where it's
like okay pop with an idea for a new
business a new system a new product
anything you don't know if there's
enough people out there who need it who
you're solving the problem for until
you've created it and then the problem
yes if you do market research but it's
still not as good as crowdfunding or do
people actually sign up before you ever
started right and you're like no no
here's my prototype how many people are
there Oh a hundred thousand people want
them and this is the price point we can
sell it out right like that's how you
set up a cars running campaign is you
realize what's that lowest threshold and
then if it goes beyond that you're
making even more profit because you're
not actually lowering emails the big
thing is is and it's not colder ship but
in this way we're saying we have a
million people who have signed on who
say yes we're willing to pay attendance
per month you're not paying $10 per
month yeah that's only happens at a very
specific point in the process but that
they're agreeing to means we have the
threshold to change worlds we have a
threshold of financial backing as well
as 1 million people putting input input
on any product we're creating
once the technology is in place to do
that can't have and that's the issue -
so the technology's not in place we
can't have a conversation with 1 million
people so let's say we did a
crowdfunding campaign overnight and this
happened like it just happens and we got
1 million people are willing to pay $10
in the beginning it's just $10 for the
first section and the next project $10
and it's not $10 per month $10 per
project until we unlock simultaneous
projects we have the threshold of users
where that becomes like there are more
hands and minds working on it then we
can support then oh look now there's two
projects three projects right once we
unlock simultaneous projects that's what
it's like just ten dollars per month
instead of ten dollars for budgeting so
people are signing up to pay ten dollars
per month to say yes when we get to that
point that excites me that's what I want
to do I want to be giving ten dollars
these aren't people we have to convince
they're gonna convince everybody else
because they're gonna be like okay
Amanda knows about but this is awesome
this isn't this is an actual hope and a
future and so that's where the
one-million becomes the threshold of
like once we have a million people
signed up but then how do you ever have
democracy and transparency with a
million people and the truth is in the
beginning we're kind of gonna suck at it
and so that's where you have the board
of directors we need a beta system so
people can give their vote to one of
those Board of Directors and that we're
transparent like what we pick 10 random
people to be on the board of directors
but your vote can go in between those 10
people then like the best of them is
going to end up getting the most votes
and they'll have the power to choose the
course of the what can be done with the
employees is what can be done with tech
earlier sorry what can be done with tech
later it's done with employees on the
backend first right so it's like okay
there if we don't have this the
technology in place to do to delegate
votes yet and we want it to be
transparent but anonymous so I know who
I'm delegated by a vote to that person
doesn't actually know it's my vote that
they have right so they can't like play
gauges to me they have to know that they
have 10,000 votes that they're from us
but not who those 10,000 are and so in
order to be able to do that maybe you
have a back-end or people just what a
million people that seems ridiculous 1
million people that you like you get to
go on and change your boat right but you
we probably need technology for that but
the employees have to create it because
I don't can't imagine we're gonna have a
million people sign in but or a million
people to have information on what the
board of directors is doing we need to
have like a reporting system
we need people to record video we need
people to make that accessible if it's
just recording let's say we're in
session for six hours we don't want to
watch six hours video someone to take
notes and distill the information down
to be able to give it to people like hey
here's what your delegate voted for
here's why they say they voted that way
right and that can be something that
employees make easier for the board of
directors who might not be able to do
that themselves I'd be able to see that
myself who did who did I can't say who i
voted for but like only if it's easy
right if i had to write that up every
time and then explain it i would not be
the best of that once you can figure out
how to make it work not have zero
conflict nothing but like less chaotic
and messy with 1 billion people you then
open it up so that those 1 million
people and you can set like if it's easy
to have a conversation with a million i
don't think if we upped it to 10 million
it's gonna be 10 times harder it's gonna
be maybe like twice as hard and even
that is probably not the case it's
probably like 8 percent more hard like
10 times population it's hard to have
conversation with a million so having
conversation 10 million is actually have
much more difficult yeah so and that's
the other beautiful thing so if we're
starting with 10 million dollars a month
we're not starting but like one channel
we don't say why don't we have like the
projects let's say it costs us 9 million
dollars a month to run the company the
employees the board of directors it
costs us 9 million dollars a month to
run that house we grow membership and we
grow projects and we grow that nine
million doesn't get increased every time
that's the beauty of working as a
cooperative so that we have let's say
that means we have 1 million which is a
little less fun to play with right but
the next time we get so then we grow up
to 2 million members well it's maybe
we'd we've increased
by that extra 10% so now it cost 10
million for us we have a whole other 10
million to play with right so as we
double membership we have more and more
and more money going towards actually
solving the problems in creating the
technology because of efficiency so
you're not reinventing the wheel every
time not every new app needs a whole new
writing team and new employees you just
need a new project and you know what
your employees are gonna go on it you
know which one's right so go try and do
it in 5 or 10 people